William G. DeLoach:
The Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library
William G. DeLoach Papers, 1911-1964
DeLoach, William G. (William Green), 1880-1967
A series of diaries chronicling the day-to-day experiences of William G. DeLoach as a West Texas farmer.
S 253.1
Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library, Texas Tech University
2 boxes (1.3 linear feet)
Biographical Sketch
William G. DeLoach was a longtime resident of Crosby County and Lamb County, Texas. His family traveled from southern Oklahoma to settle in a small farmstead in Crosby County. For fifty years, he kept a diary to record his life experiences as a farmer and family man in West Texas. Some of his diary entries have been used to compile the book Plains Farmer: The Diary of William G. DeLoach, 1914-1964. The book was edited by Janet Neugebauer. DeLoach was born in 1880 and he died in 1967.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains twelve diaries arranged in chronological order written by William G. DeLoach between the years 1911-1964. They have daily entries on weather, farming, family, community, financial entries, and other topics.
Portions of the Papers may also be viewed in digital format among the Southwest Collection’s Digital Collections.
Organization
The diaries are organized as follows:
Diaries
Index Terms
The subject headings used by the Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library are derived from the Library of Congress and/or locally developed.
Subjects (Persons)
DeLoach, William G. (William Green), 1880-1967.; DeLoach, William G. (William Green), 1880-1967--Diaries.
Places
Crosby County (Tex.)--History.
Subjects
Agriculture--Texas, West.; Farm life--West Texas.; Farmers--Texas--Crosby County.
Accession Information
Collection accession #(s): n/a
Gift, 1975
Access Restrictions
Open for research
Bibliography
Neugebauer, Janet M., ed. Plains Farmer: The Diary of William G. DeLoach, 1914-1964. College Station, Texas A and M University Press, 1991.
Related Materials:
Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library:
Mason Family Papers, 1900-2002 and undated
Collection Inventory
- Diaries
  - First Ledger, March 28, 1914 to January 16, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Second Ledger, January 17, 1916 to July 25, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Third Ledger, May 1, 1911 to July 1, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Ledger, October 19, 1922 to November 20, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fifth Ledger, November 21, 1927 to April 16, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sixth Ledger, April 16, 1930 to September 25, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Seventh Ledger, October 3, 1936 to May 10, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Eighth Ledger, May 11, 1941 to December 27, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ninth Ledger, January 1, 1946 to August 23, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tenth Ledger, July 1, 1952 to February 9, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Eleventh Ledger, February 11, 1959 to January 26, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Twelfth Ledger, March 1, 1962 to March 27, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)